ABOUT ME

I am a self-motivated and self-driven software engineer with a passion for creating software solutions from ideas and perspective of others. I am constantly learning new skills and technologies to stay focused on current software development trends and have many years of experience developing applications in enterprise settings.

CONTACT

PHONE: 330-398-4437

EMAIL: jerry-doran@hotmail.com

WEB: jerrydoran.dev

SKILLS

HTML/CSS/JavaScript

Git/GitHub

React/Next.js

Progressive Web Apps

SQL

MongoDB

SQL Server

Postgresql

Node.js/Express

Visual Studio Code

UI/UX Development

EDUCATION

ACCIS (2001 - 2004)

B.S. - Computer Information Systems

Youngstown State University (1997 – 2000)

MBA - Finance

Duquesne University (1986 – 1990)

B.S. - Physics

JERRY DORAN

ACCOMPLISHMENTS

- > Acted as the liaison between software supplier and the organization in the implementation of an MRP system resulting in \$50,000 annual savings.
- Developed database applications to manage product/process information, supplier/customer satisfaction and key departmental metrics
- Developed invoicing and reporting system for finance department through the use of automation which resulted in improved work efficiency by 40%.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

PCC Airfoils, LLC – Minerva, OH (2008 – Present)

Senior Applications Engineer

- > Develop and manage automated information systems used for evaluation of key departmental metrics.
- Provide technical instruction and training to departmental personnel
- > Database application development and deployment for various users throughout the organization.

PCC Airfoils, LLC – Minerva, OH (2006 – 2008)

Senior Engineer

- Work with plant engineering and operations to implement and control processes for new and existing product lines.
- Identified and evaluated new material and process technologies that extended product capabilities and new job startups.
- Developed quality system database to track and manage customer returns and requirements.

American Cap Company, Inc. – Wheatland, PA (2004 – 2006)

Information Systems Manager

- Developed annual business plans and key performance indicators that reflect operational performance for critical processes, methodologies and technologies within the organization.
- Developed automated database systems for monitoring company-wide performance metrics to ensure accuracy and efficiency of measurements.

Thomas Steel Strip Corporation – Warren, OH (2003 – 2004)

Manager of Quality Systems

- Developed applications and reports utilizing enterprise information systems to identify best practices.
- Developed relational databases to track departmental goals and metrics.

WCI Steel – Warren, OH (1996 – 2003)

Application Product Engineer

- > Developed and managed cost performance measurements.
- Developed and managed information systems for measuring product and process data.